RAJ KAMAL YADAV

Address: Sirawal, Beri, Koraon, Allahabad Uttar Pradesh, Pin: 212306 Contact: +91-7309680925, E-mail: kamalraj.kamal327@gmail.com

Objective

Civil Engineer with over 7+ years of experience in performing construction and maintenance of engineering projects. Particular expertise in pile foundations, earthworks, concrete works, Road works, Railway works, Roof sheeting works & Waterproofing works. Identifies and addresses challenges during construction and overcomes obstacles with creative and diversified Projects & to be the part of a Constructive & Fast Growing World.

Experience

- Presently working as Sr. Engineer/Inspection Engineer (Civil) "TUV India Pvt. Ltd" from 06 March 2020 to till now.
- QS/Site Engineer Jhajharia Nirman Ltd from 15 Nov 2018 to 15 Feb 2020.
- Site Engineer M/s S.S Kalra from 15 Jul 2017 to 30 Oct 2018.
- Site Engineer M/s N A Shaikh from 15 Jul 2013 to 15 Jul 2015.

Professional Qualification

- **2015-2017** Completed M. Tech. in Structural Engineering from SHUATS, Naini, Allahabad (U.P. State Act No. 35 of 2016, as passed by the Uttar Pradesh Legislature) with 85.5%.
- 2009-2013 Completed B. Tech. in Civil Engineering from Kali Charan Nigam Institute of Technology, Banda affiliated to Uttar Pradesh Technical University (Now Uttar Pradesh Technical University) with 73.04%.

Academic Qualification

- 2009 Passed Intermediate from Gopal Vidyalaya Inter College, Koraon Allahabad with 62.2%.
- **2007** Passed High School from CRHS Intermediate College, Bargada, Mirzapur with 65%.

Project &Internship

Road Project | Carried out project on "Civil work for construction of roads, drain, culverts, bridges, retaining wall of M/s OPAL, Dahej (Guj.)".

Infrastructure Project | NAPHTHA UNLOADING GANTRY, Civil works during MTA & Repairing of damaged acid brick lining in cooling tower 1/2/3 & RWTP of M/s OPAL, Dahej (Guj.).

Drill Site Project | Construction of foundation, other ancillary works, internal hardening, ring bund, repairing and improvement of approach road and post rig building works for Electrical rig, at Drill site GNDGX, GNDGY of M/s ONGC Ankleshwar Asset.

Railway Project | Execution of earth work in formation, construction of major and minor bridges, supply of machine crushed stone ballast, transportation of P.Way materials, execution of P.Way works, welding and other allied miscellaneous works between Chandia - Lorha (Ex) in connection with construction of Anuppur - Katni 3rd line of Bilaspur Division of South East Central Railway.

Internship | Completed summer training from IFFCO, Phulpur, Allahabad in RO System.

Technical Skills

- Perform Visual inspection of materials received at site and advising material controller on his observations.
- Check and authorize materials being issued by to Contractor as free issue based on review of test certificates / documents.
- Resolve day to day issues faced on technical matters.
- Review of Method Statements Prepared by Contractors. Ensure all safety practices are followed by contractor in line with approved method statement, JSA and work permit.
- Ensure all necessary documents are properly maintained by contractor during the execution of the work and are handed over after completion of the job.
- Ensure that the latest revision of IFC drawings are used during inspection / monitoring of the progress of work
- Highlight the field problems, non-conformity, deviations etc. using STQ
- Prepare punch list and ensure that all points are attended by Contractor
- Monitoring of quality activities at site
- Monitoring and approval of all quality control documents being maintained by Contractors
- Ensure calibration of test instruments are reviewed and maintained by contractors
- Coordinating with other discipline and other contractors for smooth execution in sequential way to manage interfaces
- Providing inputs to Planning Engineer for planning and progress reporting.
- Attend educational workshops, trainings and conferences for professional growth.
- Identify slippages or delays in constructions and adjust schedules to meet deadlines.
- Identify milestones and problem areas and accordingly recommend preventive actions.
- Work with Construction Manager to develop project plan, quality assurance plan and health and safety plan.
- Direct, lead and support other engineering and skilled personnel in managing and executing multiple tasks and projects.
- Lead and direct onsite construction teams.

- Collaborate and interact with construction teams, architects and outside project developers and consultants.
- Knowledge on AUTO CAD and MS Project.
- Taking care of QA/QC documents of the entire project including certificates, calibration, test
 results, inspection requests, non-compliance reports and site instruction/observations, permanent
 materials delivered and other QA/QC documents. Responsible for the closure of Non-conformance,
 NCR and Site Instruction, SI.
- Responsible for the quality assurance & quality control of CS works, day-to-day co-ordination, supervision and field administration.
- Stage wise inspections, witness test at site as per QA Plans.
- Witness material testing if conducted at site.
- Witness test related to civil work, supervision and surveillance of quality aspect of the civil work
- Checking the measurement sheets and Bill certification of job completed.

Key Responsibilities Handled

- Inspection & witness of testing during construction and material Inspection during site works phases.
- Documentation during project monitoring & reporting phases.
- Verification of as built drawing/as built structures etc.
- Participation in the meeting/ discussion on matters/ site related issues to above works at design centre of contractor.
- Inspection and quality assurance of the work/project is to ensure the quality control and quality assurance of the entire civil work.
- During the course of execution of the project suggest modification in the contractor procedures, method statement, materials source etc.
- Preparation/ review/ supervision/ witness/ Inspection report of the Quality management program, Quality assurance plan and quality control plans etc.
- Technical guidance specialities of experts in concrete technology, framework system, waterproofing, plumbing etc.
- Corrective action and closure of non-conformities.
- Quality review meeting as required to review non-conformities observed and monitor rectification of defects, corrective action taken.
- Onsite training, mock-up approval and work authorization.
- Checking the Quality of steel and grade of concrete as per structural requirement, diameter shape, and cement.

Area of Interest

- Software used Civil Engineering.
- BIM Implementation for the Project or Organization.
- Implementation of Project Management tool.
- Practical training on BIM projects.

Personality Traits

- Believe in the work. Theme "Work Is Worship"
- Excellent grasping power and technical skills.
- Have Good Communication Skills.
- Positive attitude and enthusiastic in team work.

Personal Information

Name : Raj Kamal Yadav Father's Name : Hari Prasad Yadav

Date of Birth : 02/01/1991

Sex : Male
Marital Status : Married
Nationality : Indian

Languages Known : English & Hindi

Hobbies : Meditation and Yoga.

Strengths : Quick learner, positive, honest and trustworthy.

Date:

Place: Vadodara, Gujrat Raj Kamal Yadav